<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cashflow | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/cashflow/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-03T20:50:37-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generating Monthly Cashflow from Chipotle]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/03/generating-monthly-cashflow-from-chipotle/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-03T20:34:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/03/generating-monthly-cashflow-from-chipotle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m a big fan of generating cashflow. Especially on stocks that show signs of trading near a long-term trendline support.</p>

<p>One of those stocks is Chipotle - check out the chart below:</p>

<h3 id="20170203-cmg">CMG</h3>


<p><a href="/images/blog/20170203/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170203/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2017-02-03 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>This is a weekly chart of CMG. The trendline support is drawn from all the way back in 2008 to the lows of 2009 and swung out to the present. We still haven&rsquo;t quite been able to touch that support recently, but when price explores that level, buyers may step in.</p>

<p>What I like to do every month is sell put spreads below that support level to collect some premium. And if I get assigned the stock, I&rsquo;ll be ok with owning some at that level (and then selling some calls on it). Here&rsquo;s a trade idea you can do every month on CMG:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/20170203/cmgps.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170203/cmgps.png" alt="CMG Put Spread - 2017-02-03 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>This is a 365/360 put spread expiring in March, currently going for about .72 credit. That translates to $72 per spread that you put on, and it only requires $500 of capital, or a 14% return on capital - delicious! Time to finance those burrito bowls!</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my tweets in real time whenever I make posts!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
