<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cashflow | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/cashflow/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-04T17:17:35-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Cover Your Cigarette Expenses]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/04/how-to-cover-your-cigarette-expenses/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-04T16:01:50-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/04/how-to-cover-your-cigarette-expenses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year, the <a href="http://finviz.com/groups.ashx?g=industry&amp;v=210&amp;o=-perf1w" title="Top Performing Sectors - 8.3% Return on Tobacco Products Sector">tobacco industry has already shown a 8.3% return on investment</a>. We&rsquo;re looking for this trend to continue. One stock in this industry is Philip Morris - the largest cigarette manufacturer in America. Please observe the chart below:</p>

<h3 id="20170204-pm">PM</h3>


<p><a href="/images/blog/20170204/pm.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170204/pm.png" alt="PM - 2017-02-04 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>PM is in a strong uptrend, breaking the 200MA and very far from the 20MA. We&rsquo;re now exploring the upper balance area set from 2016. Given the strong industry, how earnings has already passed, and that we&rsquo;re now in this upper range of balance and expect it to stay within this range, we&rsquo;re looking to collect premium in a favorable buy spot around the 200MA at $95.</p>

<p>Going over to the option chain and selecting the 95 Put strike in March:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/20170204/pmoc.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170204/pmoc.png" alt="PM - 2017-02-04 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>With the bid at .34 and the ask at .41, we can look to sell this option for around .37. Essentially we could collect about $37 by March expiration. Hey, that covers the cost of about 6 or 7 cigarette packs. Although if you&rsquo;re smoking this much a month, you should really consider cutting back, for the sake of your health.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> to receive our tweets in real time whenever we make posts!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collecting Money off Gold Put Options]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/04/collecting-money-off-gold-put-options/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-04T15:44:03-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/04/collecting-money-off-gold-put-options</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We like stocks that break the 200MA as a signal to go long. One of those stocks is $GDX. <a href="http://finviz.com/groups.ashx?g=industry&amp;v=210&amp;o=-perf1w" title="Top Performing Sectors">Being a top performing sector of the year</a>, Gold is an asset that catches our eye as an option to go long.</p>

<p>On that note, we&rsquo;d love to own GDX at the 50MA (marked by the blue curve) - that&rsquo;s near $22.50:</p>

<h3 id="20170204-gdx">GDX</h3>


<p><a href="/images/blog/20170204/gdx.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170204/gdx.png" alt="GDX - 2017-02-04 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Going to the options table, we can look to sell the 22.5 Put option expiring in March, and collect about .49 in premium:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/20170204/gdxoc.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170204/gdxoc.png" alt="GDX Options Chain- 2017-02-04 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s $49 per contract sold. If you don&rsquo;t mind buying 100 shares of $GDX at $22.50, then at least making money while sitting around and waiting for it to come down to that level would be a great way to earn some cash. This trade idea is basically the same strategy as <a href="/blog/2017/02/04/waiting-patiently-for-aapl-while-getting-paid/" title="Waiting Patiently for $AAPL While Getting Paid">that of our previous one on $AAPL</a>. Rinse and repeat is a great way to continuously generate monthly cashflow.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> to receive our tweets in real time whenever we make posts!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Waiting Patiently for AAPL While Getting Paid]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/04/waiting-patiently-for-aapl-while-getting-paid/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-04T15:11:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/04/waiting-patiently-for-aapl-while-getting-paid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re like us and you love owning a great stock at a lower price, but want to make money while waiting for it to be cheaper, then you&rsquo;ll like this options trading strategy.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the daily chart of $AAPL:</p>

<h3 id="20170204-aapl">AAPL</h3>


<p><a href="/images/blog/20170204/aapl.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170204/aapl.png" alt="AAPL - 2017-02-04 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>During such bullish times, the 20 period moving average (marked by the yellow curve) is a decent buy point. Which means, we don&rsquo;t mind owning some stock around the level marked currently by the yellow curve. An even number around this level would be $120.</p>

<p>Going to the options table, we can look to sell the 120 Put option expiring in March, and collect about .41 in premium:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/20170204/aaploc.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170204/aaploc.png" alt="AAPL Options Chain- 2017-02-04 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s $41 per contract sold. If you don&rsquo;t mind buying 100 shares of $AAPL at $120, then at least making money while sitting around and waiting for it to come down to that level would be a great way to earn some cash. If, by the time March expiration rolls around, $AAPL is still not trading near 120, then you can rinse and repeat for April expiration was well.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> to receive our tweets in real time whenever we make posts!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generating Monthly Cashflow from Chipotle]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/03/generating-monthly-cashflow-from-chipotle/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-03T20:34:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/03/generating-monthly-cashflow-from-chipotle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m a big fan of generating monthly cashflow. Especially on stocks that show signs of trading near a long-term trendline support.</p>

<p>One of those stocks is Chipotle. We all eat there every once in a while - wouldn&rsquo;t it be nice for us to pay those burrito bowls with premium we collect on this stock? If you&rsquo;re interested, check out the chart below:</p>

<h3 id="20170203-cmg">CMG</h3>


<p><a href="/images/blog/20170203/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170203/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2017-02-03 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>This is a weekly chart of CMG. The trendline support is drawn from all the way back in 2008 to the lows of 2009 and swung out to the present. We still haven&rsquo;t quite been able to touch that support recently, but when price explores that level, buyers may step in.</p>

<p>What I like to do every month is sell put spreads below that support level to collect some premium. And if I get assigned the stock, I&rsquo;ll be ok with owning some at that level (and then selling some calls on it). Here&rsquo;s a trade idea you can do every month on CMG:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/20170203/cmgps.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170203/cmgps.png" alt="CMG Put Spread - 2017-02-03 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>This is a 365/360 put spread expiring in March, currently going for about .72 credit. That translates to $72 per spread that you put on, and it only requires $500 of capital, or a 14% return on capital - delicious! Time to finance those burrito bowls!</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my tweets in real time whenever I make posts!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
