<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: volume profile | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/volume-profile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-27T20:46:30-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trading Near Prominent Point of Control]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/27/trading-near-prominent-point-of-control/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-27T05:43:36-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/27/trading-near-prominent-point-of-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Good morning traders.</p>

<p>In the <a href="/blog/2016/04/25/watch-for-an-upside-move/" title="Watch for an Upside Move">last post</a>, we discussed how trading near the POC from last Monday, Thursday, or Friday is very possible. We got exactly that yesterday, with another rip higher into the close as traders found themselves unable to take the market lower:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04272016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04272016/es.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-27 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Notice how we developed most of yesterday&rsquo;s value above 2081.75. Bias here should be neutral to slightly bullish.</p>

<p>The overnight inventory on the /ES is currently net short. We&rsquo;re currently trading around yesterday&rsquo;s POC at around <strong>2082.50</strong>, with the overnight low at <strong>2080.75</strong>:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04272016/es_reference_points.png"><img src="/images/blog/04272016/es_reference_points.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-27 - 5m Chart - Reference Points" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to see how the overnight low holds - if we break below it but are unable to find more sellers and we begin trading back above it and then through the open, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target yesterday&rsquo;s value area high at <strong>2086.50</strong>, then the overnight high at <strong>2087</strong>, followed by yesterday&rsquo;s settle, which is <strong>2088.75</strong>. Again, watch for internals to confirm.</p>

<p>As for downside references, my opinion remains the same as yesterday&rsquo;s post:</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;I would need to see the 2067 level fail. If we close below there with signs of stronger selling, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target the other side of balance, which is down at 2012. More intermediate targets would occur along the way, but they&rsquo;ll be noted when we do break 2067.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
