<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: low confidence | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/low-confidence/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-10T08:07:05-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mind the HVNs]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/10/mind-the-hvns/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-10T05:32:39-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/10/mind-the-hvns</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday&rsquo;s trade was very evenly distributed around the POC, with a small value area range, so it was a fairly decent balance day:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05102016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05102016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-10 - 5m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Traders were able to find acceptance back in the upper distributions of last Thursday&rsquo;s and Friday&rsquo;s trade. They managed to build value higher, albeit overlapping, thus not really a sign of any momentum. Again, we&rsquo;re seeing low confidence as traders have no idea where to go from here.</p>

<p>/ES is currently trading at 2062. Overnight inventory is net long. On an intraday basis, when we open, watch the internals and see if the $TICKs have a hard time reaching 0. That will tell you whether or not there is a gap fade play. If the $TICK quickly shoots downwards, here are some downside targets for the gap fade:</p>

<ol>
<li>yesterday&rsquo;s high at 2057.75</li>
<li>value area high at 2056.75</li>
<li>POC at 2054</li>
<li>value area low 2051.50</li>
<li>yesterday&rsquo;s low at 2048.25</li>
</ol>


<p>Note the High Volume Nodes (HVN) at around <strong>2051</strong>, <strong>2075</strong>, and <strong>2085</strong>. Remember that prices tend to get pulled in those directions. With the /ES currently at 2062 (low volume node), expect prices to migrate away from here and possibly find acceptance near one of the HVNs.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. If you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my tweets in real time. I&rsquo;ll be posting all of my trade entries, adjustments, and exits.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Low Confidence Continues]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/09/low-confidence-continues/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-09T05:44:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/09/low-confidence-continues</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday we formed two distributions:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-09 - 5m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Traders took the market back up to the upper distribution formed on Thursday.</p>

<p>Overall, the market last week moved lower, but did so with a bit of a forced action. Ultimately traders found themselves unable to take the market much lower in multiple sessions, and by the end of these sessions, we saw an end of the day rally. Furthermore, value areas were mostly overlapping throughout last week, meaning it seemed hard for the Bears to get any sort of momentum to the downside or a trend going at all. All of this spells low confidence to me.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m remaining neutral going into this week until things change. For downside targets, I&rsquo;ll be watching last week&rsquo;s RTH low at 2033.75 and overnight low at 2030.50 to see how those hold. For upside targets, we have high volume nodes at around 2075 and 2085. If we have any sort of a rally, I&rsquo;ll be looking to put on a trade that captures a move into those areas, for a credit.</p>

<p>Here is a brief look at the major market indices on the weekly.</p>

<p>SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Still holding below trendline resistance, and has room to fall to the downside to the 38% Fib.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This one is holding well above the trendline support.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>As the weakest of the bunch, it&rsquo;s spent a long time grinding lower and is holding above the 50% Fib.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Just closed below the trendline resistance last week. Let&rsquo;s see how that trendline acts as resistance this week, however.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this weekend/morning market outlook. We&rsquo;ll be doing more trade adjustments today, so as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me there</a> to receive tweets about our trades in real-time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
